My only love sprung from my only hate.
Romeo + Juliet is a drama, romance film directed by Baz Luhrmann.
In director Baz Luhrmann's contemporary take on William Shakespeare's classic tragedy, the Montagues and Capulets have moved
their ongoing feud to the sweltering suburb of Verona Beach, where Romeo and Juliet fall in love and secretly wed.
Though the film is visually modern, the bard's dialogue remains.
Romeo, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Juliet, played by Claire Danes.
Balthasar, played by Jesse Bradford.
Captain Prince, played by Vondie Curtis-Hall.
Ted Montague, played by Brian Dennehy.
Tybalt, played by John Leguizamo.
William Shakespeare's Romeo & Juliet (stylized as William Shakespeare's Romeo + Juliet) is a
1996 romantic crime film directed, produced, and co-written by Baz Luhrmann.
It is a modernized adaptation of William Shakespeare's tragedy of the
same name, albeit still using Shakespearean English.
The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio and Claire Danes in the title roles of two teenagers
who fall in love, despite their being members of feuding families.
Brian Dennehy, John Leguizamo, Miriam Margolyes, Harold Perrineau, Pete
Postlethwaite, Paul Sorvino and Diane Venora also star in supporting roles.
It is the third major film version of the play, following adaptations by
George Cukor in 1936 and by Franco Zeffirelli in 1968.
The film was released on November 1, 1996, by 20th Century Fox.
It was met with generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
over $147 million against its $14.5 million budget.
At the 47th Berlin International Film Festival in 1997, DiCaprio won the Silver
Bear for Best Actor and Luhrmann won the Alfred Bauer Prize.
At the 69th Academy Awards, Catherine Martin and Brigitte Broch
were nominated for Best Art Direction/Set Decoration.
In 2005, the film was included on the BFI list of the "50
films you should watch by the age of 14".
The film was also re-released in Luhrmann's Red Curtain Trilogy DVD box set in
2002 together with Strictly Ballroom (1992) and Moulin Rouge!
The film explores themes of suicide, gang war, forbidden
love, based on play or musical, murder.
The tone is emotional.